So today we've got pineapple, coconut
cream, some cherries, and a Ninja Creamy
Deluxe container. And that can only mean
one thing. If you like
Yeah, I have no hat.
Today's hat, pinina colada. It is a
blend of pineapple, coconut cream,
sweetened coconut cream actually, and
rum. Apparently, it was originally done
with a light rum, but modern variations
change to light and dark combined. Or
just use whatever rum you have to hand.
And then garnish with a pineapple wedge
or a marishino cherry, a candid cherry,
a glass cherry, all of those things. So,
we're going to get all of those things
combined into a perfect panina colada
ice cream in the Ninja Creamy. Now, I
live in Canada and getting glass
cherries here is pretty much impossible.
I can get them on Amazon, but they're
like 30 bucks for a 100 gram pot, which
is just insane. And I'm not paying that.
If you're in the Americas, then they're
called candid cherries. And if you live
in Europe, they're called glass
cherries. Same things. But in in the
Americas, actually, you've got much more
choice and options as to what you have.
So, in Europe, glassy cherries, they're
marishinoa cherries generally that are
soaked and cooked in a sugar syrup for a
long time until they're basically
translucent. Um, they're delicious and I
would eat the entire tub. But over here,
you can get light cherries, dark
cherries, sweet cherries, sour cherries,
loads of different choices. So, the
first thing we're going to do is prepare
our pineapple. And rather than buy an
entire pineapple, which I actually just
can't eat, I've gone to Walmart and
bought a can of pineapple chunks in
pineapple
juice. This can is
540 ml. So, what we're going to do is
we're going to take a little pan here
and we're going to empty that entire can
into
this little saucepan. So, with that in
there, we are going to start heating
this up on hob, medium heat. We want to
get that boiling. We want to get that
reducing down. And we're going to turn
this into a really strong boozy rum
pineapple It's just a fancy name
for a sauce. On to the cherries. We're
going to use sweet cherries, product of
the US. I have no idea what type they
are, but
I don't know. First thing we're going to
need to do is we're going to need to pit
these. So, we've got 400 g of our
cherries. Invert sugar. Invert sugar is
like corn syrup.
You actually can use high fructose corn
syrup here if you really want to. Um
I've not actually seen it in shops here
in Canada. Um, maybe it's just a US
thing, but uh, glucose syrup, corn
syrup, golden syrup, those kind of
things. Proper inverted sugar. You can
make inverted sugar at home. It's not
really very difficult. Less chat, more
cherries. 400 g of cherries. That's
including the pits and the stalks and
everything. So, 400 g. So, with our
cherries done, we're going to put those
into our pan like so. We're going to add
a little bit of water. So, and onto that
we're going to put 200 g of sugar. Now,
remember this is 400 g of cherries. So,
now we've got our sugar in there.
We are just literally going to put it on
a hob and we are going to heat this up
until we get to a soft boil stage, which
is this
invert sugar.
There we go. That is our invert sugar.
Amounts listed in the description.
I'll put them on screen now as well.
That invert sugar will stop the
recristallization of the sugar over
time. So obviously we're making a large
batch here. We're not going to use all
of these in this pan ice cream. So
they'll last for months and months and
months because of that invert sugar. So
on the hob this goes. This is the rum I
have. This is the rum I'm going to use.
I'm not buying anything specifically for
this. But we don't want to put this in
when the pineapple is hot. So, with that
in mind, we're going to take this off
the hub
and we're going to let that cool down
for a good while. We need to get that
almost down to room temperature. So,
let's leave that there for about 2 hours
and then we'll add the rum in. Right,
our cherries are finally up to
temperature, 135 fah. It's like 113
centrade. 235 Fahrenheit, sorry. About
113 centigrade. we're going to do is
just take them off the heat and just let
them completely cool down to room
temperature. I shouldn't have to tell
you that sugar is bloody hot. Be
careful.
So, while that's just bubbling away,
cooling down, we've got our cooled down
pineapples in our pineapple juice. So,
that's now cooled enough that we can
process it. There's a couple of things
we need to do. We need to add our rum.
And we need to thicken this as well. So,
what we're going to do is thicken this
with zantham gum. Zantham gum because
specifically this is an acidic food.
Guard does not work well in acidic food.
So that is why we're going to use
zantham gum. You can use as much or as
little as you want depending on how
thick you want it. I'm going to go
straight in at 3 g, which is just over
half a teaspoon of our zantham gum.
Going to sprinkle that on there because
we're going to blitz this now in our
little baby blender.
With that blended,
there's only one thing left to do, and
that is let's get that into there.
We're going to not make this super
smooth. I kind of still want, you know,
some chunks of pineapple in there, but
do it however you want. If you want it
thin, super super smooth, then strain it
through a fine mesh sie. And there is
our
pineapple. And we are going to add in
75 grams of rum. And we're going to stir
that together. And we have a super super
boozy rum pineapple. And now we're going
to let this completely cool down in the
fridge overnight. Once our cherries are
down to temperature, room temperature,
we're just going to put those in a
container. Store those in the fridge as
well. Now the ice cream base. So, in the
description below, there are two
versions of this recipe. This one, which
is plant-based, and another one which is
not and has the dairy in it. Coconut ice
cream with a little bit of dairy in is
infinitely better than all these because
milk solids does something to ice cream
that is just impossible with any other
ingredient. It's unfortunate that those
on a dairyfree diet um can't experience
that, but that's just
the way it is. Let's get everything out
of the cupboard that we need. Right,
everything we need, inulin or another
substitute, plant-based fiber. Just be
careful using other fibers. Not all of
them are created equal. Some will make
it go really kind of gloopy. Uh, inulin
is great. We're not using a huge amount
in this recipe, so it's not going to
upset the apple cart, if you know what I
mean. Um, this disgusting stuff, which
is arythrtol monk fruit,
has no place in making decent ice cream
apart from adjusting the freezing point.
Uh, so in this, we're actually only
going to use like 12 g of this in our
recipe. We are going to use alulose.
It's not available in Canada. I ordered
this in. You can do the same in Europe.
You can use xylitol. If you use xylitol
in Europe, it's much easier to get hold
of. You will have to use less than is in
this recipe. So, I think what we at?
We're at 90 grams cuz we're making a 750
gram batch. I would probably bring that
down to about 55 grams if we're going to
use xylitol. Uh, we're going to use
zantham gum again because we've used it
already. And we have our coconut cream
and our coconut milk. So, let's get
everything in a pan and going. Why do
you keep going back to milliliters?
Thank you. 165 g of coconut cream, 439 g
of our coconut milk. We are 20 g short.
In comes the water.
g of inulin. 12 g of arythrtol. You got
to be accurate with this stuff. If you
put 20 g in, your ice cream is going to
really struggle to freeze. This is
really, really strong.
Like antifreeze for food, if you will.
90 g of alilos. 2 and 1/2 gram of
zantham gum. That is everything. We put
that into there to break up the zantham
gum. As we've got a fair amount of fat
solids in here, we need to heat this up
a little bit. We don't need to go crazy
because zanthan gum is a cold processed
stabilizer. So, let's just put that into
there. Pop this on the hob for 5
minutes. Get it up to, you know, 40 to
50° centigrade, which is this in
Fahrenheit. And then we can take it off.
Right. With our cherries now cooling
down, they are going to look like this.
[Music]
Literally 5 minutes.
That's all we have that on for. Nice
texture, good consistency.
Into our Ninja Creamy tub.
[Music]
Exactly 750 gram. Smells delicious. That
is now going to go in the freezer
overnight. And tomorrow we'll do
everything and create this delicious pin
colada ice cream. So I will see you
tomorrow.
[Music]
Perfect texture. No ninja creamy hump.
It's uh it's not a difficult thing to
resolve, but we got a really nice white
coconut ice cream.
[Music]
[Applause]
Peanut colada ice cream. coconut ice
cream base with super boozy rum
pineapple. Fancy word is but
let's just be honest, it's a sauce. And
homemade candid cherries or in Europe
they're called glass cherries. These
I want to just try one of these before I
get into the ice cream. Oh, they are so
good. For openness and honesty, I had to
do the cherries three times. First two
recipes didn't work, but the last one
did. The last recipe is this. It's down
in the description, and this came from
Bigger Boulder Baking. Gemma is an Irish
chef, and most of her recipes are really
decent.
So, that's the one I used for this, and
the result is incredible. Apparently,
they will keep for basically ever in the
fridge. So, that's what I'm going to do.
Keep them in the fridge. I'm going to
use these in ice cream. I'm going to use
them in baking, cakes, you name it, I'm
going to use them. So, they'll go in
there. There's so much alcohol in this
that this will probably outlast me in
the fridge as well. Not enough talk.
Let's eat ice cream.
That coconut base is delicious.
Super smooth, really strong coconut
flavor. Perfect texture. There's
absolutely nothing wrong with that. And
no added sugar as well using the alulos.
The rum, that rum pineapple cuts through
really nicely.
It's not so strong that the rum
overtakes everything. And the cherry
with a bit of everything.
Delicious. The cherry is to imitate the
cherry decoration that would go on the
glass. Sometimes a pineapple wedge,
sometimes a cherry, sometimes both.
Thanks very much for watching. Don't
forget to like and subscribe. I hope you
try the pinina colada ice cream and I
will see you next week.
[Music]